[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 4]
[Grace of Cloud and Water]
Morning, Grand Commander.
It's already past 7 a.m.
Seems like the Ministry of Justice
doesn't enforce strict discipline.
Thanks to you,
I slept extremely well last night.
How sure are you that the murderer isn't
from the second branch of the Liang family?
90 percent.
Go investigate quickly,
while your head
is still on your shoulders.
If you keep making me
stay up all night,
even if my head is still here,
I'll have to lose my life anyway.
Sir.
Sir, Madam,
breakfast is ready.
I have no appetite.
Oh my,
what a mess.
Yan Xing.
Xing!
Chuichui.
Seriously?
Doesn't the Shen's Mansion provide meals?
I'm afraid I might...
She's still alive.
choke eating with him.
She seems fine.
Let's go.
Choke?
Come on.
I heard that you and White Ghost
are deeply in love,
like a
harmonious couple.
I've heard about you
riding together.
Tell me about it.
Indeed.
Good news doesn't travel far.
Bad news spreads like wildfire.
Bad news?
You're now
famous among the noble ladies
of the Imperial City.
Back then,
there was a woman who pretended to faint
and fell into Shen Du's arms
and was arrested by the Imperial Security Bureau
for offending
the Grand Commander.
That's so typical of him.
Ever since then,
women in Xiang'an City
avoid White Ghost
like the plague.
But he showed affection to you in public,
even intimate contact.
Better keep a distance.
What's going on?
On the night of your wedding,
the Ming Hall caught fire.
The Grand Empress Dowager was furious.
Several people from the Imperial Security Bureau
were held accountable.
Even your husband
had his salary docked.
Really?
I heard that
the poor scholar named Chen Baiyi
set himself on fire
in the Ming Hall because he failed
to achieve official rank.
Now he's dead,
and his family should have been implicated.
However,
all that's left of his family is
this nearly 60-year-old,
half-blind and deaf old lady.
The Grand Empress Dowager was merciful
and had pardoned her.
But then this old lady
went to the entrance of the Ministry of Justice
and sat for a long time,
demanding justice.
She sat there for a whole day and night.
Just imagine,
who would dare to
take this case?
Are you out of your mind?
I'm going to lose my head either way.
I only have one head anyway.
Ma'am,
please get up first.
If you really have a grievance,
we'll definitely
look into it.
Thank you, young lady.
[Yuan's Chang'an Collection]
Who's so bold
to take that old lady's complaint?
Come on,
step forward.
I'm in a good mood today.
I promise not to beat you to death.
Who took her complaint?
You mean the old Mrs. Chen at the gate?
I've already sent her home.
Dismiss.
Let's go. Dismiss.
Let's go.
[Feng Gui]
Why is it always...
Actually, the old lady
should be properly comforted.
Otherwise, it'd be improper
for her sitting in front of
the Ministry of Justice every day.
Regarding Chen Baiyi's self-immolation,
I've already
-investigated the case...
-I'll leave the follow-up to...
Feng Gui!
Keep an eye on the old lady for me.
Don't let her come again.
Not me, please.
Director Wu,
I think...
Everyone, gather around.
The case of Liang Chenzhong's murder has been
taken over by the Imperial Security Bureau.
No one
is allowed to interfere.
The Imperial Security Bureau
is not a place
to meddle with casually.
Anyone who disobeys
will be severely punished.
-Yes.
Get back to work now.
Director Wu, I...
Yan Xing.
Chuichui.
Haven't you two finished
organizing those files yet?
Work hard.
I really...
Xing,
I suddenly remembered
the Grand Commander Shen
invited you for lunch, right?
It's about time.
Well,
the case files aren't that urgent.
Lunch is more important.
Let's go.
[Tongming House]
Give up your little business.
Follow me.
Alright.
I'll rely on you then.
My apologies, Madam.
[Ministry of Justice]
Tongming House only
serves male guests,
not female guests.
We're not guests.
We're here on official business.
Then why not
send a male official instead?
I'm just a scribe,
but this one here
is a registered ninth-rank
official from the Ministry of Justice.
If you keep blocking us,
could it be that
you have objections to the government's
official selection system?
[Tongming House]
Madam, please don't make things difficult for me.
If I let you two ladies
in today,
I'll
probably
lose my job.
Why don't you
take another look?
Are we male guests
or female guests?
Male guests.
Please, come in.
[Tongming House's Owner, Rong Zhui]
My poor Zhanxin,
how could she be so miserable?
I thought she'd
become a proper concubine
with Liang Chenzhong.
Who could be so heartless
as to kill her?
My condolences.
Do you remember
if anything unusual
happened before
Kuang Zhanxin disappeared,
or did she have
any disputes
with anyone?
Zhanxin was always gentle
and got along well
with everyone.
Before the officials informed you last night,
you didn't know
that Kuang Zhanxin was missing?
She left on the 17th of last month
to go on an outing with Liang Chenzhong.
Liang Chenzhong often
took her out for fun.
I thought this time
they were just gone a bit longer.
If we need anything else in the future,
we'll come back to ask.
My condolences.
I heard that Chen Baiyi set himself on fire
and burned down the Ming Hall.
It's good that you drove him out early.
The Cang State practices nepotism in official appointments.
He's just a poor man
trying to climb up.
It's simply a pipe dream.
It's his honor
to polish my writings.
But he still wasn't satisfied.
These poor scholars
are so ungrateful!
A tutor
trying to win
first place in the Hongwen Academy's competition?
Bah!
Let's drink.
Come on.
Xing.
Let's go.
Xing?
Commander Xu?
Secretary Lu.
Commander Xu,
you came to Tongming House for a case?
The case that
your husband took over.
I guess I shouldn't
call you Xing anymore.
I should address you as Mrs. Shen.
Commander Xu,
you can call me
Xing as usual.
Alright.
Then don't
call me Commander Xu either.
Call me Xu instead.
Okay.
Xu.
After the news about
Kuang Zhanxin spread,
the owners around
Pingkang House
all went crazy.
They thought
any girl who left
and didn't come back
was missing.
A dozen cases have been reported already.
Are there more people missing?
No.
17 girls were reported missing,
but 15 have already been found.
There are still two left.
They should be fine too.
But there's one thing
I haven't decided whether
to report or not.
And then I ran into you here.
[Missing Persons Case Files]
These files record
the cases of missing performers over the years.
[Missing Persons Case Files]
[Qiuying, female, age 20, a singer from Yongle House]
[In the late summer of the first year of Yuanhe, on August 17, a commoner named Cao Meimao testified]
Strange.
Although not all of
these performers were
the top ones in their houses,
they all understood music theory
and excelled in instrumental music,
especially the pipa.
That's right.
It's too much of a coincidence,
which is why it seems suspicious.
These are portraits of the missing women.
These women
all have the same hairstyle.
Anything else?
Look,
although their faces
[Xiaohe, from Guanghan in Yizhou, 1.7 meters tall, good at playing pipa]
are different,
they all have something in common.
Especially their expressions
are very similar.
Yes,
at first glance,
there's an indescribable similarity.
I was planning
to give these files to the Ministry of Justice,
but I thought
it's improper to bypass the Imperial Security Bureau.
Now it seems
it's best for you to take them.
At least White Ghost
won't kill his wife over this.
Right?
I'll take my leave then.
You were so determined before you left
this morning.
I thought you went investigating,
but you're just chatting here.
I'm discussing
the case with Commander Xu, who leads all the constables
in the city.
Leads all the constables?
That impressive?
Commander Xu was
once a famous outlaw with a bounty of
100,000 taels on his head.
So Commander Xu
is the legendary one
who snuck into the palace
and stole the Grand Empress Dowager's jade pillow.
Sounds impressive,
but he still got caught.
Although he was caught,
the Grand Empress Dowager valued his talent.
Not only did she not punish him,
but she also freed him from slavery.
Still, getting caught
means he was
outmatched.
I...
What kind of case could you
discuss with someone like him?
Of course I can.
I'm about to win the bet
about the Liang family.
The current evidence
all points to
a series of murders that have been
happening for years.
Once I find the real culprit,
the second branch of the Liang family can
be completely cleared of suspicion.
Grand Commander,
people watching the Liang family reported
that the second branch of the Liang family
had been splashed with chicken blood by the main branch.
Second Madam Liang became even more deranged.
And Third Young Master Liang
turned himself in to the Ministry of Justice.
Also,
Princess Ying wants to see you.
[Guangyue Restaurant]
Princess Ying
requests to see only the Grand Commander.
Your Highness.
Liang Chenyu has been imprisoned.
This is not what the Grand Empress Dowager wished for.
If I remember correctly,
the Grand Empress Dowager
did not ask you to thoroughly
investigate this case,
but to protect the second branch of the Liang family.
The evidence is not sufficient at the moment.
No conclusion has been reached yet.
You've always been meticulous in your work.
But this time,
you're not following the rules as usual.
Don't follow in your father's footsteps,
quietly making big moves.
I wouldn't dare, Your Highness.
Princess Ying must be
giving the Grand Commander a hard time.
Regarding the Liang family case,
the Grand Empress Dowager has already instructed
to protect the second branch of the Liang family.
But you
insist on investigating it thoroughly.
Now look what's happened.
Third Young Master Liang has been imprisoned.
How can the Grand Commander
explain this to the higher-ups now?
I will take full responsibility for this case.
I will definitely provide
a satisfactory explanation.
The Grand Empress Dowager trusts you,
and so do I.
I just hope that you
will not betray this trust.
I heard that Mrs. Shen
is quite an interesting person.
The Grand Empress Dowager has bestowed this marriage.
It's my great honor.
Grand Commander,
five pairs of corpses
were found at Ximing Temple,
with the same cause of death as the previous two.
It seems
this case is indeed
unrelated to the second branch of the Liang family.
Including the previous two bodies,
there are six pairs of men and women,
12 bodies in total.
The killer's method is the same for all victims:
the men's hearts were removed,
and the women's faces were disfigured.
This isn't soil from Ximing Temple.
These bodies
have been moved recently
and reburied.
The face is dark purple,
with flesh turned outward.
But I can still tell
this is a young woman.
Can you estimate
the time of death?
These two
were likely killed last month.
There's a lot of
charcoal and ashes around the bodies,
probably to cover up the smell.
What's that strange scent?
Anything unusual?
If my master were here,
he'd be able to identify
what's in this.
In my opinion,
you've already inherited
your master's skills.
You're no less than
the famous folk detective Pan Chi.
I'm far from that.
After my master retired,
he's been traveling around.
I'm afraid he has forgotten
about me.
This is
the earliest pair of bodies found,
severely decomposed.
The time of death
is difficult to determine precisely.
It's likely
between four to six years ago.
If it's the same killer,
that's utterly insane.
A heart ripper.
The killer must be
a strong man,
perhaps a butcher.
In my opinion,
the killer is most likely
a woman.
Why?
The cuts on each woman's face are almost
identical
in position,
length,
and depth.
It doesn't seem like
the work of a man.
If the killer's a woman,
she would have had to
kill 12 people over these years.
These male victims
weren't weak or infirm either.
They were all in their prime when they died.
How could they possibly be overpowered by a woman?
Xu,
if we dismiss something
just because we haven't seen it before,
then many strange cases in this world
would remain unsolved forever.
Let's go.
What...
What exactly are you doing?
Princess Ying has already ordered
that the Ximing Temple case
and the Liang's Mansion case
be combined and handled
by the Imperial Security Bureau.
The Ministry of Justice
can no longer interfere.
Alright then.
I'll take you somewhere first.
Where are we going?
You...
In her sleeves,
it's the scent of white brain incense.
A silk brocade robe with ruyi patterns.
A jade floral hairpin.
A white silk fan with peony patterns.
If you have time to daydream here,
you'd better think carefully
about how to keep your head.
Where exactly are we going?
The Ministry of Justice.
Put me down now.
We're almost at the Ministry of Justice.
I can walk there myself.
The real culprit hasn't been found yet.
Third Young Master Liang is still in prison.
If anything happens to him,
you'll be joining him in the grave.
Grand Commander Shen,
I, Yan Xing, have never
lost a bet.
What brings the Grand Commander
here today?
Can't I come?
Grand Commander, what are you saying?
Welcome, welcome.
I'm here to request someone
to help at the Imperial Security Bureau.
You want to transfer someone?
That's easy.
Who do you want?
I'll arrange it right away.
Her.
The 10 corpses case at Ximing Temple
has been fully handed over to the Imperial Security Bureau.
The Ministry of Justice should not interfere anymore.
Understood.
Grand Commander,
there are still many case files
that I haven't finished recording.
I'm afraid I can't be transferred to the Imperial Security Bureau.
What are you saying, Miss Yan?
If the files aren't finished,
hand them over to Secretary Lu.
You go with the Grand Commander now.
If Miss Yan doesn't come,
the case will just be closed.
Director Wu,
take those corpses outside the city
and bury them anywhere.
No way.
I'll go right away.
Xing,
these were found at Chen Baiyi's house.
I've read all the articles
he wrote.
Each piece is brilliantly written.
Thank you
for your hard work.
It's okay.
Watching opera at Furong Garden?
Approved.
Be careful.
Grand Commander,
the coroner has completed the preliminary analysis.
Jing Lin.
If it's discovered later
people from the Ministry of Justice investigate the case privately,
they will all be dealt with as factionalism.
Yes.
Then I must thank you
for your patronage, Grand Commander,
allowing me the right
to investigate this case.
I will do my utmost to solve the case
as soon as possible.
I'm glad you understand.
[Report]
Since I've been transferred to the Imperial Security Bureau,
I'm now
a member of you
and must follow
your rules.
I'm just a mere scribe.
How could I ride a horse
with the Grand Commander?
My horsemanship is poor.
Guard Jing, you care for the subordinates
and surely
wouldn't leave me behind.
Isn't that right?
Me?
Then I'll have to
bother you
to share a ride with me.
Madam, if you wants to ride a horse,
you should ride with the Grand Commander.
I...
I'll lead the horse for you.
That would be inappropriate.
Let's ride together.
There's no gender distinction in solving cases.
Guard Jing,
just treat me as
an ordinary colleague.
Madam, please sit properly.
Are you done chatting?
If you keep being so casual,
I'll dock your salary for half a year.
I... I...
Grand Commander.
These
were taken from the first
pair of victims' bodies.
It was marked
in the first year of the Shengli era.
This belonged to
the first male victim.
The killer's first crime
must have been six years ago.
Why?
The killer's method
is identical every time.
The time of the crimes
must also follow a pattern.
As the saying goes, "A tiny mistake can
lead to a huge error."
If our deduction is wrong,
finding the real culprit
won't be so easy.
The double fish pattern.
Jinxiu Workshop?
This double fish pattern
was a special design
created by Jinxiu Workshop
that swept across the country.
Jinxiu Workshop was the largest silk workshop
in the Imperial City at that time.
They presented silk to the palace on the first day of every month.
However, in June of the third year of Shengli,
Jinxiu Workshop was accused of treason
for making summer clothes for Princess Runing that exceeded regulations.
They were charged with the crime of insubordination.
So after that,
no one in the Imperial City
dared to wear fabrics from Jinxiu Workshop in public.
This man
must have died
before the Jinxiu Workshop treason case.
The gold medal was made in the first year of Shengli.
It's possible that the man died
in the same year.
Impossible.
The double fish pattern
was from the third year of Shengli.
It was a spring clothing style made by Jinxiu Workshop,
only sold from February to April that year.
You remember it so clearly.
There are
files of old cases from Jinxiu Workshop in the archives.
There's an illustrated catalog
that records
ten years of pattern styles from Jinxiu Workshop.
Jing Lin,
go and verify it.
There must be no mistake.
Yes.
[Chang'an City]
Madam,
the archives room
is full of precious items and rare books.
Please don't wander around,
and don't touch anything.
I know.
We'll find it faster if we split up.
You go that way.
Remember, don't touch anything.
[Compilation of Selected Test Essays from Hongwen Academy]
Compilation of Selected Test Essays from Hongwen Academy.
[Essay Four: In the empty mountains, dragons weep with sorrow, and heaven shines brightly]
Be quick with your hands.
Hurry up!
Don't drop anything.
What's going on here?
Wait a moment.
Hold on.
Why are you here?
Weren't you transferred to
the Imperial Security Bureau?
I need to see Director Wu.
There's been progress in the Chen Baiyi self-immolation case.
The director has said
no one is allowed to
mention the Ming Hall case again.
If anyone asks again,
they should submit their resignation.
There's really something fishy about it.
I want to see Director Wu.
Wait, wait.
Can't you see?
The entire Ministry of Justice today
has been thrown into chaos
by a nursery rhyme.
Who has time
to investigate the self-immolation case?
Right?
What nursery rhyme?
You don't know?
It's serious.
It's spread all over
the Imperial City.
I wonder this time
who's going to suffer.
Slow down.
Watch out for the steps.
People are heartless.
Buddha eats hearts.
Chaos reigns under the Son of Heaven's feet.
Buddha devours hearts to conceal sins.
The Black Rakshasa is here.
Kid,
do you realize what you just said
is extremely treasonous?
Tell me,
how should I punish you?
Try this new invention called
"Get into the Urn."
Later,
we'll put the urn over a fire,
and you'll have even more fun.
Guards!
-No! My lord!
-No!
-My lord!
No! My lord!
-No!
My lord, he's just a child.
I beg you to spare him, my lord.
Spreading such
treasonous words.
Doesn't that make
the Imperial City
a lawless place?
-No, my lord.
-My lord, he's innocent.
If you don't properly educate your child,
then I'll do it for you.
Please don't, my lord!
Make way for the Princess Ying's carriage!
Your Highness.
This person looks familiar.
What's all the commotion about?
Your Highness.
I beg you, please save my child!
Your Highness,
I came to patrol the streets today,
and suddenly heard a child speaking
treasonous words.
That's why we apprehended the child.
I apologize for disturbing you.
I see.
Please have mercy, Your Highness.
The child spoke without thinking.
I'll take him home
and teach him properly.
Yes, Your Highness.
If a child is not taught properly,
it is the father's fault.
You cannot escape blame for this.
Lord Lai,
everyone makes mistakes.
Moreover,
this is just a young child.
You've always been wise.
Why tarnish your reputation
over a mere child?
Though that may be true...
Since I've encountered this child today,
it means
this child and I are destined to meet.
Lord Lai,
could you spare this child
for my sake?
Since Your Highness has asked,
of course I'll release the child.
Release him.
-Thank you, Your Highness.
-Thank you, my lord.
It's good that the child is okay.
Thank you, my lord.
You may go.
-Thank you, Your Highness.
Princess Ying
truly has a heart of gold.
Princess Ying is truly magnanimous
and full of compassion.
Farewell, Your Highness.
Go back and get 20 strokes!
Yes.
Who is that woman?
[Imperial Security Bureau]
What's wrong?
Lai Luozhi went to the palace to complain,
saying the Grand Commander isn't handling the case well.
The Grand Empress Dowager
has taken him away.
You two, guard the entrance.
If there's any news about the Grand Commander,
report it immediately.
Yes.
[Grand Commander's Office]
No one is allowed in.
Grand Commander ordered,
without permission,
no one is to approach the office.
Whoever disobeys…
If you...
If you want to break in,
you'll have to step over my body.
Stop it.
If you do it again, I won't be so nice.
Stop it!
If you keep doing this, I'll kill myself!
If you don't want to
save the Grand Commander's life,
then go ahead.
Grind the ink.
I hope it's not too late
to submit the report.
[General, Yu Shikun][Left Commander of the Shence Army, Zhao Jun]
[Imperial]
[Imperial Security Bureau]
It's actually the same handwriting
as the Grand Commander's.
Are you sure
this can really
save the Grand Commander?
I can't say for certain he'll be fine,
but we have to at least try.
[General, Yu Shikun][Left Commander of the Shence Army, Zhao Jun]
Perhaps it can spare him from severe punishment.
What are you waiting for?
Go quickly!
I'll wait for you here.
Stop rummaging through them.
[Cangming Hall]
Your Majesty,
the Imperial Security Bureau has handled the case for days
but hasn't solved it.
Now rumors are spreading that
the court is incompetent in appointing officials.
Some even speculate that the court's
deliberately protecting the Liang family.
This is damaging your reputation.
Your Majesty, I humbly request to let
the Imperial Investigation Department take over.
Lai, what you say
is exactly also my concern.
Shen Du from the Imperial Security Bureau has arrived.
Your Majesty, I, Shen Du, the Grand Commander,
pay my respects to you.
Long live the Grand Empress Dowager.
Mr. Shen,
the Liang family case
remains unsolved.
Don't you think you should
give me an explanation?
Your Majesty,
the Liang family murder is not an isolated case.
It is connected to the multiple bodies
that have been found at Ximing Temple.
They were all committed by the same killer.
The Imperial Security Bureau is already working on
combining the cases based on the evidence.
The Liang family case involves high-ranking officials.
Moreover, Ximing Temple is
a place for quiet worship and meditation.
Now, with these unsolved cases,
a disturbing nursery rhyme has spread in the city.
Its content is quite offensive.
Let's hear it.
Please allow me
to recite this nursery rhyme
for Your Majesty.
People are heartless.
Buddha eats hearts.
Chaos reigns under the Son of Heaven's feet.
Buddha devours hearts to conceal sins.
How dare you!
Please calm down, Your Majesty.
I believe
this nursery rhyme has spread
because the Ximing Temple case
remains unresolved.
If the Imperial Security Bureau still can't find the real culprit,
perhaps holding
an exorcism would be
more effective.
The Grand Empress Dowager's dignity is unmatched.
There's no need to concern
with these absurd superstitions.
Grand Commander Shen,
did you forget this?
The guards suddenly came to arrest me.
I was just organizing the case details
to present them to you, Your Majesty.
"In a peaceful world, only the Buddha's heart remains.
All evil thoughts vanish, never to return again.
Unraveling the truth, washing away the unjust.
With keen insight, the world finds peace and trust."
Very good.
Well, since
you've already uncovered
many clues about the Liang family
and Ximing Temple,
then proceed with the investigation.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Mr. Shen,
you also mentioned in your report
that there's more to the self-immolation at Ming Hall.
The immolator
was not expressing dissatisfaction,
but rather using death to convey a message to me,
as a last resort.
Is that true?
I'm currently double-checking
and will report back soon.
Your Majesty.
Alright, alright.
You two
are like my right and left arms,
each with your own strengths.
Alright.
Let's call it a day.
You may all leave now.
Mr. Shen,
please stay.
I have another task for you
to handle immediately.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Grand Commander Shen,
today in front of the Grand Empress Dowager,
you remained composed,
with a silver tongue.
It's truly admirable.
Lord Lai, I'm flattered.
I was merely stating the facts.
People say
the Imperial Security Bureau
is the Grand Empress Dowager's eyes.
But if those eyes keep darting around,
they might focus on the wrong things.
The actions of the Imperial Security Bureau
are all within our duties.
Unlike the Imperial Investigation Department,
with its fangs tearing at everything in sight.
If it were someone else,
they might be overwhelmed.
Then I hope
you solve the case soon.
Afterall, there are many people
sharpening their teeth now.